[Music]
it can be really hard to talk to the
camera so this is really good practice
for me i was gonna do a q a
in october but just things worked out in
a certain way that i realized it might
be just better to do it this week
instead and if you are not interested in
a q a don't worry at all i will be back
next week with my more usual content i
thought it would just be fun to get a
little more personal and learn about you
guys as well because i would love if
you there was a a paraglider
in the air and my dog saw him in the sky
and just freaked out he's he's still
freaking out some people wondered how
you pronounce my name one thing that i
do to explain how to pronounce it is
that it rhymes with hola in spanish like
hello in spanish
hola rhymes with my name paola
so you kind of break it up you go la
paola the other common question was my
birthday and i was born december 5th
i am 24 years old i'm gonna be turning
25 this december which feels monumental
so it's really exciting
my brother he is 23 and my sister is 27
and her name is lyanna and my brother
who you guys kind of know already his
name is rohan so another question i got
was about my parents and
the languages i speak
and my father he was born and raised
here in washington state actually
and my mother she is native puerto rican
i would definitely say i am fluent in
english and spanish but my
spelling in spanish is not very good i
had quite a few people ask me how i'm
doing and i thought that was really
sweet so i wanted to say
thank you i'm doing very well thank you
very much for asking it's been a very
relaxing lovely month for me if you had
to choose a different path for yourself
what would it have been if i had chosen
a different path
i think there is a
likelihood
i would have gone on to do more advanced
studies in english literature
and i might have become a professor but
it just it just wasn't the right time
you know and and i wanted to
experiment a little more with my more
creative side it was very important to
me to find ways to involve my art and
creativity into my daily life and being
a professor
didn't seem like the right path at this
time also when i was much younger when i
was a teenager i was very convinced i
was going to be a veterinarian
i cared a lot about animals and working
with them and it was something very
meaningful to me i think i will always
have rabbits in my life they're such
sweet and kind and
gentle creatures if
you were able to raise them from
very young and teach them to be
comfortable with humans i've just always
enjoyed them but yes being a
veterinarian was definitely not the path
for me another great question i got was
what do you do to relax and i wanted to
go over that because it's probably some
things that might surprise you i
actually am a bit of a nerd and i love
board games
and thankfully my brother and my dad and
my boyfriend all love board games as
well that is one thing i love to do to
relax it's always wonderful because i
get to spend time with my family too and
recently one of my favorite games to
play is called everdell and i will show
you some images of it because you will
see why it is all based off around
little adorable animals
and
it's it's really cute so
this is definitely not a game for people
who
have never tried board games before
because it is a bit complicated to learn
but if you're already kind of
experienced with more nerdy board games
you will definitely enjoy it i think
another thing i do is that i have a
little mini projector it's really cheap
so the image quality is not that great
but i love to project it on my wall at
night
and it has a speaker too so i can play
kind of ambient music and i really enjoy
that at night it's very relaxing
i also love lighting candles that is
actually a brand new hobby of mine
so i have recently
amassed a little bit of a candle
collection and i really love them and
there's a adorable fantasy inspired
candle business i love that i
shout out on instagram a lot because how
much i love it and um i will leave the
link to them down below too if you're
interested in some fun little more nerdy
candles as well so
i also love to go to fantasy fairs and
renaissance festivals i've not been able
to go to that many
this year because none of them have been
happening but there is one happening
soon that is outdoors where you can
still kind of keep social distancing and
so i think that's really great you know
um so i hope to go to that one and i
will definitely share that one with you
so those are some ways that i like to
relax there's many more but kind of
those are the main ones candles board
games fantasy fairs
projectors you know it's it's all
sounding more and more nerdy as i think
about it but
yeah obviously reading too i love
reading um and listening to audiobooks
i got a lot of questions and requests
for book recommendations so
to prevent myself from talking for three
hours about my books and not getting to
any other questions i've put a lot of my
favorite books down below
as well as taken that opportunity to
answer some really common questions that
kept popping up if your question isn't
answered on the video please check down
there and if i still don't get to your
question i hope to do another one of
these at some point in the future so
one very good question i got from
several people was what are the
downsides of living rural what are the
downsides of
your lifestyle right now and there is
definitely downsides of living out here
as opposed to
the city one of them is that when you
are in such a rural area there just
aren't that many people you may not be
able to find a large group of people
that share some of your hobbies or
interests
and so that is definitely something that
you need to keep in mind before moving
very rural that that can be challenging
but also you know my experience here has
been that
i really have embraced learning about
new people with all types of different
backgrounds and interests and even
though they don't share my interests i
can still
learn and gain a lot from
knowing them so it all depends on your
personality and
how important it is for you to have a
large group of people that are similar
to you or have a similar background to
you
another downside for me personally is
kind of a very
silly one and that is internet
connection it's not always easy to find
a really good internet connection it
would be really nice to have wi-fi in
this house
just because it would make
working a little bit easier i wouldn't
have to
move somewhere else in order to use my
computer and all that it's something
silly i don't need it so i and i make it
work i think living rurally sometimes
forces you to face a lot of small
inconveniences
you are forced to separate what you need
with what you want and seeing what you
want as convenience things that aren't
always necessary to
live happily you know so it's
it's been really good it's for me you
know but it completely depends on who
you are and what type of job you have
you know some people are completely
prevented from living more rurally
because they need to rely on a very
stable internet connection so it
completely depends i got one really cute
question that i just had to answer
really quick and and it was what is your
favorite flower
and
that changes every single day because i
love all flowers and i'm obsessed with
them
and
sometimes i put way too many flowers in
my house and it just pretty much smells
like pollen so
yeah i love flowers but i would say
currently my favorites are flax flowers
another question i got was what made you
move to your cottage from the city
and i think the answer to that is really
boring i needed a job
so again like i mentioned before i i
worked in customer service and i lived
in a university town that really only
offered more minimum wage customer
service positions and it would it was
really hard to find a job that helped me
move forward a little bit and put some
savings in the bank and be able to
really plan for the future so i i
applied to be a school teacher over here
and i was able to get that position and
it gave me the perfect amount of
stability while i worked on my art
business and got that going and now i've
been able to do that full-time
that is that is a dream come true so
i'm so thankful to all of you who've
shown your support you know to have
to to be able to have my um
business allow me to be creative
but also
have something that is completely my own
and to be able to create art and even
these videos and
all that has just been so meaningful and
it's just
transformed my life in many ways so i'm
i'm very thankful for that so
i really i'm really thankful for that
okay
another question i loved was what is the
most exciting thing about the
countryside for you and i love that
because again wherever you live there
are positives and negatives you know and
for me the positives are being able to
hike and walk anywhere and i just love
that it is just so much fun to take my
dog and let him
you know really experience the world so
freely and being able to bring my camera
and share those places is so exciting
because i feel like i can
support this valley and support this
area and one of the most
meaningful ways for me which is to be
able to
bring awareness to natural areas and
consequently help preserve them and
plant trees and
you know inspire people to get involved
but that's
definitely been a driving force in
everything i do in regards to this
channel another fun question was about
safety a lot of people were interested
in what it's like to live so near
wildlife and
i
always find this question very
interesting because i personally have
never experienced a lot of anxiety about
wildlife but i have come to realize that
a lot of people do these animals
especially predators
and they want to be left alone i'm not
fearful of them but of course that is
never a reason to just throw caution to
the wind you know you want to go on your
hikes with your bear spray and
you know whatever you need to go with to
feel safe but
it doesn't feel dangerous to me another
question i had was about being alone and
being lonely in the middle of nowhere
you know and that's also one i wanted to
address because i have very active
relationships with my family i have my
boyfriend in my life i have a lot of
people in my life but
i care a lot about not
forcing people to be on camera if it
makes them uncomfortable even though i
have neighbors
and i have
a lot of people in my life
they're not seen on camera very much i
hope that explains things a little bit
one of the very first questions i got
after i asked it on instagram was if i
get angry and if i lose my temper
and i laughed at that one because it was
really funny i've actually had a bit of
a journey in regards to that i am not
someone who loses their temper very
often and i don't think i feel very
intense anger very often
and i don't think that is always
necessarily
a good thing because
for some personalities it can be really
hard to be assertive and
sometimes be louder and to be very clear
with how you feel and what you want and
what is frustrating you while that
doesn't mean losing your temper and
being disrespectful to other people or
you know
there's nothing wrong with getting upset
sometimes and being very clear with how
you feel in fact it can be very
liberating to
be honest with people
when you really need to while losing
your temper may not always be the best
thing i don't think
suppressing how you feel and not being
assertive when you need to is a good
thing either
for me i've actually gone on a bit of a
journey of trying to be more clear with
what i want and more clear with what is
frustrating me and what
um
i need
another common question i get is where
is your clothing from
and
there is a reason that i have never
answered this question and that is
because
i have a lot of family members and
extended family that gift me clothing
and i have a lot of clothing that i get
from thrift stores which is one of my
favorite places to find clothes i don't
share the brands because i'm not i don't
want to encourage people to just go buy
brand new clothing from these brands i
try to wear
you know the clothes i already have and
secondhand clothes and
i enjoy
dresses and all that but clothing isn't
a big part of my life every dollar i
spend on something else could be
something i spend on a book
so
you know if anything is going to grow
exponentially it's going to be my book
collection i got a question about my
boyfriend and how i met him we were
actually set up
by my mother
i wasn't happy about it initially but uh
things changed and worked out very well
so
i had one question from a woman asking
what
strategies
i use in order to deal with grief
and
that's a hard question because i think
it you know every person deals with
grief differently
but i will say this and it is some words
that were given to me by an old friend
they described
losing for example losing someone
important in your life or having a
really a time of um a loss as
you become a living memorial to the
people that you have lost i really like
that idea that we
continue to breathe and walk this earth
as memorials to people we have loved and
we no longer have in our lives and
through that we keep them alive i i love
that way of looking at it a time of
grief after losing someone will always
be transformative while you cannot
physically bring back those people in
your life you can
share their story i hope that makes
sense but thank you for that question
you know it's one i will have to think
more about
and speak more on in the future another
question was what do you think is the
bravest thing you have ever done i will
say a silly thing and a not so silly
thing i think the silliest brave thing
i've ever done is gone skiing
i spent
a portion of my childhood in puerto rico
and then i spent a lot of it in the
south of the states as well and my
mother is from the tropics as well so we
just never
experienced winter sports very much and
i went skiing for the first time last
year and it was
just about the scariest thing i've ever
done
my mother is outside it's okay
another thing that i would consider
brave is something i do try to do often
and is
to be open to yourself and really seeing
your actions and your feelings and
everything in a very honest light
and authentically asking yourself if you
are wrong i encourage myself to look at
things from different perspectives and
understand people i think it's very
brave to try to have those interactions
with an open mind one of the bravest
things maybe is to come up to someone
and say i'm sorry
or also when equally necessary to say i
love you saying sorry
and reminding people we love them are
two very important things that
all of us need to do not all human
interactions are about who's right and
who's wrong you know sometimes it's just
about
love
are there snakes here yes there are
snakes there are rattlesnakes and bull
snakes and
all all types of snakes in this area
yeah but again just like bears and
cougars and predators they really don't
want to be bothered you know so um it's
definitely something to be aware of and
be careful about some people thought i
had built this cottage and that it is
off-grid
and um i have not built this cottage
i've built fairy houses before they've
been about this big and very
foundationally unsound so there you go
the second and last question i got was
about english and what i studied in
university i assume there are at least
several students watching this so i
don't know if this will be helpful to
you but at least i can share kind of
what i did so i ended up applying to
university college of dublin in ireland
and i had a lot of fun i i did gain a
lot from it and i enjoyed it and i
enjoyed studying english over there but
i ended up wanting to go back to the
united states
once my parents also moved back there
i've always
been very family oriented and it means a
lot to me to just be near my my parents
and my siblings so that was always the
motivating force in all my decisions
even coming over here so yeah i finished
my literature degree and actually in a
western washington university in
bellingham i think with a lot of degrees
in the arts you can make it
a lot more or maybe even slightly less
challenging depending how you approach
it and how much time and energy you put
into it and i cared a lot about my
degree and
i was thinking about being a professor
so i put a lot of effort in my english
degree and it has been extremely useful
and it has helped me a lot especially in
the area of presenting myself in writing
in a very
eloquent way
i learned a lot i read a lot of books
i create started my love of just
historical children's literature and
yeah and it was very
very fruitful i i really enjoyed it
lastly a couple people were wondering if
i'm ever going to write a children's
book and for sure yes i have a lot of
ideas for children's books i would love
to write one in the future i have not
quite had time but i am actually working
on
a book for adults right now so
that is something i've been working on
for about
three three four months now and i hope
to have something produced by next year
so
i'm very excited about that it's been a
lot of fun and i'm trying to do a lot of
illustrations for it and photography so
we will see where that goes but but
definitely i will write a book and a
children's book in the future that is an
enormous goal of mine again i answered a
lot more questions in the description
bar so if i didn't answer it do check
that out because
i didn't want this to be too verbose
well i
know that you guys asked a lot more
questions but i can't
remember any more of them right now so
um i think i will leave it there
but yeah i hope to introduce you to my
family very soon they have
agreed to be part of a future video and
i would love for you guys to meet them
and
that's something else that will come up
in the future i will see you next week
with my more usual content but let me
know if you enjoyed this because um it's
kind of fun to do from time to time and
i would love to get more comfortable in
front of the camera because that's a
goal of mine and it's hard to do i don't
know how so many people do it so well so
wishing you all a wonderful day or night
and i will see you next week goodbye
you